Thanmai Ravoori

(608) 571 8885 | travoori@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/thanmai-ravoori/

SUMMARY

Certified and experienced Associate Developer specialized in Guidewire Policy Center Configurations and Integrations, with proficiency in SQL, JAVA GOSU and SOAP web services. Currently pursuing a Master's degree in Management Information Systems, with a strong emphasis on System Analysis & Design, Managing Application Databases and Business Process Integration using SAP S/4 HANA, and Business Analytics.

EDUCATION

M.S in Management Information Systems – Northern Illinois University (NIU) – Expected graduation by Dec 2024. CGPA: 3.77.

B. Tech in Electronics and Communications Engineering – Vignan Institute of Technology and Science (VGNT) – 2021. CGPA: 7.98.

SKILLS

Tech stack: Java - Gosu, Python, SQL, and Web Services. (SOAP)

Domain Expertise: Insurance – Policy Center, Billing Center, and Claim Center.

Version control: Git/Bitbucket, and Jenkins.

Tools: Advanced Excel, Guidewire Studio, SAP S/4 HANA, and SSMS.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY:

Business Consultant – Experiential Learning Center (NIU)

08/2023 - present

- Collaborated with McDonald's as part of the Experiential Learning Center to conduct in-depth research into their organizational needs and requirements.
- Project's end goal is to recommend an Enterprise managing software solution, incorporating digital transformation strategies to address their specific challenges.
- Working on presenting a comprehensive plan outlining the 'why' and 'how' of implementing the Enterprise level software system, demonstrating a strong ability to bridge theoretical knowledge with practical business solutions.

Associate Developer 2 – PricewaterhouseCoopers (PWC)

09/2021 – 12/2022

Client: Grange Insurance company and United Services Automobile Association

Role: Guidewire Configuration Developer

- Solid experience in Guidewire studio (Policy Center Configuration & Integration).
- Significant working exposure on product designer, XML configurations, activity patterns, underwriting issues, queries to find the impacted policies.
- Experience with Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment tools and procedures such as Jenkins, Git and familiar with Jira, Confluence and Agile methodologies.
- Liaised with GISO and SMEs from Grange (a client insurance company) on urgent production issues.
- Worked on Job wizards, Batch process, prequalification questions, system tables in Policy Center.

IT Intern – Defence Research & Development Laboratory (DRDL)

05/2018 - 08/2018

• As an Intern at DRDL, I have developed a home automation system using Arduino with Bluetooth being remotely controlled by an Android OS Smart phone.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

 Managing Application Databases (Skill demonstration project): Designed an application database (ERD) using Lucid chart and draw.io for a Musical Instrument Retailer, normalized entities up to 3NF, collected data from multiple datasets through Kaggle.com, performed data exploration and analysis using SQL in SSMS and presented insights.

Automatic Vehicle Number Plate Detection

- o In this project, the number plate of the vehicle is identified by image identification technology.
- The images are thereby used to trace the number using algorithms based on OpenCV framework and send an alert email to the respected email id using an embedded section for the automatic detection.

• Indoor Positioning System

- o Designed a mobile application to track a person's position inside a building using Android Studio.
- o The system worked based on RSSI values scanned from the WIFI signals around the mobile device.
- **Reverse Parking Sensor Using Arduino**: Built a prototype using Arduino and Ultrasonic sensor which can measure the distance between the car and the object and warn the driver.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Guidewire Specialist Certification Policy Centre 10.0 Developer.
- Guidewire Associate Certification Insurance Suite 10.0 Developer.
- Guidewire Insurance Suite Developer Aspen, Banff, Cortina New features.
- PCAP Programming essentials with Python by Cisco Networking Academy.
- Certified as a Frontend Developer by PIRPLE.